John F. Cummings

Experience in internships, research, and a Formula One style engineering team in various industries have provided me with the sense of intuition and technical skills required to solve complex engineering problems.

Email: johncummings115@gmail.com Website and Portfolio: www.john-cummings.com Phone: (703) 408-9003

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/john-cummings1

Education

Lehigh University

Bethlehem, PA

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering

May 2021

Minors: Aerospace Engineering, Business

Professional Experience

Relativity Space

Los Angeles, CA

 Relativity Space is a Launch Provider automating the manufacturing of rockets by integrating intelligent robotics, software, and proprietary metal 3D printing technology with an overarching goal of making space more accessible.

Additive Hardware Intern

August 2020 – Present

- Assisting with the design and manufacturing of the world's largest 3D printers, tackling problems never seen before.
- Designing integrated hardware to improve the autonomy, print quality, and reliability of these printers.

Structures Interr

May – August 2020

- Responsible for the design, analysis, and manufacturing plan of the flight side Hold Down brackets and Quick Disconnection Plates.
- Assisting with the design of adjacent structures and Ground Support Equipment that interface with the Hold Downs and Quick Disconnects.

SAVIT Corporation

Rockaway, NJ

May - August 2019

- Mechanical Engineering Intern
 - Obtained Secret Security clearance.
 - Assisted in the mechanical analysis of different adhesives for the bulkhead insulation on the XM11-13 Rocket Assisted Projectile.
 - Worked on a small team to integrate electronic and mechanical parts in prototypes and perform research on 3D printing with polyether ether ketone (PEEK), a polymer with high temperature and strength applications.
 - · Performed Geometric Dimensioning and Tolerancing (GD&T) on engineering drawings, improving the manufacturing accuracy of parts.

Project Experience

Additive Manufacturing: Life Analysis Research Group

Undergraduate Research Assistant

August 2019 - Present

- Working on a research team tasked with studying the microstructure of additive manufactured metals in comparison to wrought metals.
- Modeling the strength of 3D printed parts made by an in-house Wire Arc Additive Manufacturing (WAAM) printer based on thermal, audio, and physical data.
- Using collected data to evaluate how to adapt printing in real time to optimize grain growth and reduce defects.

Lehigh Formula SAE Racing Team

August 2017 – Present

June 2020 – Present

- Responsible for teaching SolidWorks to new members.
- Designed and manufactured a novel pedal box which greatly simplifies manufacturing without sacrificing weight, ergonomics, or functionality.

Driver Ergonomics Design Lead

May 2018 – June 2019

- Developed an ultralight carbon fiber seat and composite steering wheel, using 3D printing to produce molds and increase ergonomics through custom designed driver interfaces.
- Implemented additive manufacturing in composites molding and tube jigging as a cost-effective and ergonomic replacement for conventional methods of manufacturing.

Aerodynamics Designer

Chassis Team Designer

August 2018- June 2019

 Assisted in the designing and manufactured the nosecone and sidepods, increasing aerodynamics while minimizing weight and manufacturing cost.

Skills

Programs: Siemens NX, Ansys, PTC Creo, SolidWorks, AutoCAD, Microsoft Office Suite, Finite Element Analysis (FEA), Arduino (C/C++), LabVIEW, MATLAB

Technical Knowledge: Structures Analysis, Additive Manufacturing, Geometric Dimensioning and Tolerancing (GD&T), Machining, TIG Welding, MIG Welding, Injection Molding